#### Contact

hilavalensia@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/hila-fish (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

HashiCorp Vault Infrastructure System Architecture

## Languages

Hebrew (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

#### Certifications

PlatformCon 2023 Speaker AWS Well-Architected Proficient GCP Essentials PlatformCon 2024 Speaker

# Honors-Awards Top Dog Collaborator

## Hila Fish

Solutions Architect @ Amazon Web Services | Public Speaker | WTM & Hashicorp Ambassador

Israel

## Summary

A dedicated SRE / Infrastructure / DevOps Engineer with over 15 years of experience

Firm believer of #DevOps culture - it drives a company to perform at its best.

I aim to enhance and stabilize the business by taking care of its infrastructure, utilizing DevOps practices.

I mentor & deliver workshops on public speaking, DevOps (tools, practices, methodologies), career navigation, work skills as Incidents Management and more. DM me if you think these are useful for you or your department.

#Infrastructure is my Forte. My technological arsenal is comprised of: Architecture design (Inc. VMs/K8s integration with various AWS/GCP services, while considering costs, security, and business needs). IaC and Configuration Management tools & practices (Terraform, Ansible, Chef).

CI-CD (Jenkins, GitLab).

Monitoring & Observability (Prometheus, Grafana, and asking loys of questions).

Python - Go-To programming language.

Favorite OS - Linux's various distributions.

Managing E2E complex and cross-teams technological projects with the core notion of meeting the company's goals by leveraging DevOps practices in the best consistent way possible [See "projects" section below].

## Experience

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Solutions Architect

#### November 2024 - Present (7 months)

Tel Aviv-Yafo, Tel Aviv District, Israel

Trusted advisor for AWS enterprise customers.

Help shape their cloud journeys.

Wix.com

Senior DevOps Engineer

December 2021 - November 2024 (3 years)

Maintain all infrastructure aspects for the Data Engineering guild, that handles massive data, digested and processed daily.

Palo Alto Networks Senior DevOps Engineer 2019 - 2021 (2 years)

Tel Aviv Area, Israel

- \* Sustain thousands of GCP projects 100% Linux-based environments (Production, Dev, QA).
- \* Design and deploy infrastructure using code (Terraform, Kustomize, Helm), decreasing the manual work to a minimum (5-10%).
- \* Docker applications & infrastructure CI-CD Using Jenkins, which led to a 30%-50% increase in developers' & QA productivity.
- \* Manage thousands of Kubernetes clusters & troubleshoot issues in a fully K8s containerized environment.
- \* Monitoring & alerting of 100% of Production systems using Prometheus & Grafana, thus helping gain visibility for business SLAs & needs.

#### Highlights:

\* Awarded the "Top Dog Collaborator" recognition by collaborating efficiently with the entire R&D department (More than 10 teams) and other POCs in the company.

#### Main project:

Migration project, E2E, under a tight schedule, without harming developers productivity/delivery.

Pipl, inc.
DevOps Engineer
2018 - 2019 (1 year)
Petah Tikva Area, Israel

- Nourish 100% Linux-based infrastructure (Production, Dev, QA) and Docker applications.
- Shorten main company's processes runtime by 20 weekly hours, by automating them using Ansible, Terraform, and Python.
- Monitor 100% of Production systems by utilizing Prometheus & Grafana capabilities.

#### Main Project:

Revitalized the backup policy for the main business processes (Data Pipeline & acquisition) while reducing costs of storage usage on a big data scale, estimated at ~\$30k savings per month.

#### Taboola

Senior System Administrator 2017 - 2018 (1 year)

Ramat Gan, Tel Aviv District, Israel

- Optimize processes using new systems and technologies, minimizing their daily maintenance by 25%.
- Amend Taboola network stability by upgrading and revising 40% of its network infrastructure (FW, Switches).
- Improve visibility & observability capabilities by the construction of monitoring infra (Zabbix) on 100% of Production IT systems.

## SafeCharge Senior System Administrator 2016 - 2017 (1 year)

Ramat Gan Area, Israel

- Uphold 100% of Production infrastructure (Storage, Backups, Application/ Web Linux & Windows servers).
- Lead and implement the User Identity integration project (CyberArk FIM) to allow corporate users to access production resources securely, increasing their productivity by 50%.

#### Main Project:

 Building the monitoring infra from scratch, taking into account business needs, increasing the productivity and observability capabilities of the NOC team by 100%.

888.com Senior System Engineer 2010 - 2016 (6 years)

- Responsible for maintaining & enhancing the Production environment in 7 data centers (Thousands of servers, hundreds of data and infrastructure systems)
- Analyze complex issues (40% apps & 100% infra), to meet the company's SLAs and decrease downtime.
- Documentation Author 90% of the team's technical docs and processes that were used by the on-call personnel, thus shorten MTTR of production incidents.

#### Highlights:

- Sole focal point for the 5 business partners (Being the face of the Production team), with a lot of emphasis on excellence without compromising collaboration, thus help build the company's relationships.
- Primary maintainer of Active Directory services, which held 100% of the entities that the production systems relied on.

#### Main Project:

• Technical aspects e2e executor (Inc. coordinating the work with 2 different teams) on a DB subnet migration of critical company's applications without any downtime, keeping the company's SLA intact.

#### **HP-OMS**

HelpDesk/System administrator August 2007 - July 2010 (3 years)

System administrator on HP, "Milky Way" project on IAF. This role included:

- \* Maintaining 100% windows servers.
- \* Introducing 2-3 major IT projects for expedition of high sensitive applications performance in IAF.

## Education

#### OpsSchool

DevOps culture, tools and processes, Python, AWS, Elastic stack, CI/CD with Jenkins, Terraform, Ansible, Kubernetes, Prometheus, MySQL · (2018 - 2018)

#### John Bryce

CCNA · (2017 - 2018)